<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><!-- generator="FeedCreator 1.7.2" --><rss xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>Pink Floyd News - Brain-Damage.co.uk</title>
		<description>The most recent, biggest -hitting news about Pink Floyd, direct from http://www.brain-damage.co.uk</description>
		<link>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk</link>
		<lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2013 17:49:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
		<generator>FeedCreator 1.7.2</generator>
		<image>
			<url>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/images/M_images/rss.png</url>
			<title>Pink Floyd</title>
			<link>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk</link>
			<description>The most recent, biggest -hitting news about Pink Floyd, direct from http://www.brain-damage.co.uk</description>
		</image>
		<atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/brain-damage-news" /><feedburner:info uri="brain-damage-news" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><item>
			<title>Roger Waters: The Man Behind the Wall</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~3/hRB-a395mW0/roger-waters-the-man-behind-the-wall.html</link>
			<description>Roger Waters: The Man Behind the Wall (http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/161713564X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8 camp=1634 creative=19450 creativeASIN=161713564X linkCode=as2 tag=braindamage-21) is a new boAmazon UK (http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/161713564X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8 camp=1634 creative=19450 creativeASIN=161713564X linkCode=as2 tag=braindamage-21), Amazon.com (US etc.) (http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/161713564X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8 camp=1789 creative=390957 creativeASIN=161713564X linkCode=as2 tag=braindamage-20), Amazon.ca (http://www.amazon.ca/exec/obidos/ASIN/161713564X/braindamageon-20), Amazon France (http://www.amazon.fr/exec/obidos/ASIN/161713564X/braindamageon-21), Amazon Germany (http://www.amazon.de/exec/obidos/ASIN/161713564X/braindamage0f-21), Amazon Espana (http://www.amazon.es/gp/product/161713564X/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8 tag=braidama01-21 linkCode=as2 camp=3626 creative=24822 creativeASIN=B00AMPY4U0) and Amazon Italy (http://www.amazon.it/exec/obidos/ASIN/161713564X/).&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~4/hRB-a395mW0" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 17:28:24 +0100</pubDate>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/latest/roger-waters-the-man-behind-the-wall.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
			<title>Nick Mason signing limited edition print and fans' memorabilia</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~3/M1-g89sOr4Y/nick-mason-signing-limited-edition-print-and-fans-memora.html</link>
			<description>Rockarchive (http://www.rockarchive.com), which was established by ace photographer Jill Furmanovsky in 1998 with a view to make her own work (including her wonderful shots of Pink Floyd), and the work of other rock photographers and visual artists, more accessible to fans and collectors, are holding a very special event soon.


None other than Nick Mason will be holding a signing at their pop-up gallery in Monmouth Street, London WC2 on Thursday, May 30th. The gallery itself will be open every day from 11am &amp;ndash; 7pm until Monday, June 3rd, but we suspect those fans who are free on the 30th will be making that their priority.


Nick will be available at the Rockarchive pop-up between 5pm - 6pm to sign an edition of 50 exclusive photographic prints of himself at the drums, made specially for the occasion by Rockarchive, available at a reduced price of &amp;pound;100 for the night only. To see the picture selected for the special print, visit the Brain Damage Facebook page (http://www.facebook.com/BrainDamageUK). Pink Floyd fans are also invited to bring along one item of personal Pink Floyd memorabilia that they wish to be autographed. In addition to meeting Nick they will also be able to admire the extensive collection of Pink Floyd prints displayed in the gallery, including works by the late Storm Thorgerson and enter a raffle to win a signed pair of Nick's drum sticks.


The event is being held as part of a special 20% off traffic free shopping evening running throughout Seven Dials and St Martin's Courtyard between 5pm - 9pm. All prints displayed at the Rockarchive Pop-up Gallery are being sold at a 20% discount for the evening. For those unable to make it to the new pop-up store there is opportunity to view the extensive gallery of rock and roll prints at Rockarchive's online site www.rockarchive.com (http://www.rockarchive.com).&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~4/M1-g89sOr4Y" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2013 17:03:04 +0100</pubDate>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/latest/nick-mason-signing-limited-edition-print-and-fans-memora.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
			<title>Roger Waters - Ca Ira, Brazil 2013 - video &amp; pictures</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~3/J2Gp_K_jgHs/roger-waters-ca-ira-brazil-2013-video-pictures.html</link>
			<description>Theatro Municipal de S&amp;atilde;o Paulo (http://www.prefeitura.sp.gov.br/cidade/secretarias/cultura/theatromunicipal/) has this month been host to four very special performances of the opera by Roger Waters, Ca Ira. First performed live to much acclaim in Rome, Italy, in November 2005, it has subsequently had further live performances in countries as diverse as Poland, The Netherlands, and Brazil, who last hosted it in 2008 (a report, with various photographs and video clips, can be seen here (http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/archive/roger-waters-a-ira-in-brazil-pictures-and-video-clips.html)). Lika Geribello, the executive producer of those performances, produced the new ones alongside Cristiane Rossetto, and thanks to Lika, and photographer Bob Toledo, we have a selection of pictures from the event below.


We've also got a selection of pictures from the venue and performance, from John Floyd, who also got his programme signed by Roger - you can see this to the left. As with the pictures below, click the thumbnail to see the image larger. The contemporary new look and feel to the performance comes across vividly in the photographs below, and we hope that this new production can be seen elsewhere at some point in the future.


Just prior to the pictures, below, here's a video of Roger being interviewed about this new adaptation:&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~4/J2Gp_K_jgHs" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 16:12:23 +0100</pubDate>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/latest/roger-waters-ca-ira-brazil-2013-video-pictures.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
			<title>Any Port in a Storm - new exhibition opening</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~3/3noTjnrejLo/any-port-in-a-storm-new-exhibition-opening.html</link>
			<description>Portsmouth Guildhall (http://www.portsmouthguildhall.org.uk/events/any-port-in-a-storm) on England's south coast (venue for a number of early Pink Floyd concerts, including the first FULL live performance of The Dark Side of the Moon in January 1972), is the latest host of the absorbing, iconic, and thought-provoking artwork by the late Storm Thorgerson and the teams of Hipgnosis and StormStudios who collaborated with him on all the pieces.


'Any Port in a Storm' opens tomorrow, May 12th, and runs until June 22nd, 2013. The venue are hosting it in their new Zodiac Gallery, following recent refurbishment work. Of Storm's recent passing, the venue noted that  We are  saddened by the recent passing of Storm Thorgerson. Our thoughts are with his family and friends during this difficult time. It is a privilege to be able to commemorate this great artist by exhibiting his work at Portsmouth Guildhall. The exhibition will go ahead as Storm wanted it to. 


It is free entrance to the exhibition, and the gallery is open Monday to Friday, between 9am - 5.30pm, and on Saturdays between 10am - 4pm. Please note that the the Zodiac Gallery will be closed on Saturday May 25th, and that the exhibition will move to the Portsmouth Room from June 15th - 22nd.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~4/3noTjnrejLo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 13:28:30 +0100</pubDate>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/latest/any-port-in-a-storm-new-exhibition-opening.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
			<title>Aussie Floyd's Jodrell Bank DSOTM show - win a pair of tickets</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~3/1OkpJDJvHAU/aussie-floyds-jodrell-bank-dsotm-show-win-a-pair-of-tickets.html</link>
			<description>Back in February (http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/latest/aussie-floyd-special-one-off-show-to-celebrate-dsotms-40th-annive.html) we noted that The Australian Pink Floyd, who first played in the UK twenty years ago for the first International Brain Damage fan convention at Wembley, will be performing at Live From Jodrell Bank on Saturday 6th July. The highly regarded tribute act will be playing a special celebration show to mark the anniversary of the release of Pink Floyd's most well-known album, in a truly eye-catching location. Jodrell Bank, in Cheshire, is part of the University of Manchester and is a world renowned British observatory that hosts a number of radio telescopes.


A unique element of the Live From Jodrell Bank shows has seen bands beaming their projections on the huge, 76 metre Lovell telescope and The Australian Pink Floyd Show with its audio visual production are sure to be using this to the best of their abilities in this special environment. 


Courtesy of Live from Jodrell Bank (http://www.facebook.com/livefromjodrellbank) we've got a pair of tickets to give away to our Facebook followers for the upcoming show. The support acts have been announced now, and are Hawkwind, Richard Norris's Time   Space Machine and The Lucid Dream. Just pop over to the facebook.com/BrainDamageUK (http://www.facebook.com/BrainDamageUK), where you'll find the competition post.  Like  and share the photo to be in with a chance of winning... the winner will be announced on our Facebook page next weekend.


If Facebook isn't your sort of thing, tickets are currently on sale through this direct link (http://www.livefromjodrellbank.com/tickets) for this special, one-off performance.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~4/1OkpJDJvHAU" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2013 11:17:16 +0100</pubDate>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/latest/aussie-floyds-jodrell-bank-dsotm-show-win-a-pair-of-tickets.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
			<title>Roger Waters' Ca Ira in Brazil - video</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~3/CjDhz3eMafo/roger-waters-ca-ira-in-brazil-video.html</link>
			<description>The Theatro Municipal de S&amp;atilde;o Paulo (http://www.prefeitura.sp.gov.br/cidade/secretarias/cultura/theatromunicipal/)
is currently host to the latest performances of the opera by Roger Waters, 
Ca Ira. First performed live to much acclaim in Rome, Italy, in November
2005, it has subsequently had further live performances in countries as
diverse as Poland, The Netherlands, and Brazil, who last hosted it in 
2008 (a report, with various photographs and video clips, can be seen here (http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/archive/roger-waters-a-ira-in-brazil-pictures-and-video-clips.html)).
Lika Geribello, the executive producer of those performances, is also 
producing the new ones alongside Cristiane Rossetto. The first two shows took place on Thursday (May 2nd) and Saturday (May 4th), and the remaining shows will take place at the world-renowned venue on Tuesday and Thursday (May 7th and 9th, 2013). To date, the shows have been extremely well received, and the production has been given a contemporary new look.


With musical direction and conducting by Rick Wentworth (who also 
co-produced the album with Roger), there are vocal performances from Lina 
Mendes, Gabriella Pace, Keila Moraes, Marcos Paulo, Giovanni Tristacci, 
David Marcondes, Leonardo Neiva, Eduardo Amir and Leonardo Pace. There 
is also be a children's chorus, and the Coral Lirico do Theatro 
providing the main chorus line. The Orquestra Sinf&amp;ocirc;nica Municipal are performing the score, under the watchful eye of Wentworth and 
assistant conductor, Luis Gustavo Petri. For these productions, the 
Director is Andre Heller-Lopes, with the set design by Renato Theobaldo,
costume design by Rosa Magalhaes, and the lighting has been designed by
Fabio Retti.


More information can be found on the venue's official website (http://www.prefeitura.sp.gov.br/cidade/secretarias/cultura/theatromunicipal/).


In the meantime, here's a look behind the scenes at the production:&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~4/CjDhz3eMafo" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 21:28:17 +0100</pubDate>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/latest/roger-waters-ca-ira-in-brazil-video.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
			<title>Italian Pink Floyd Day II and launch of Floydseum</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~3/3CHTuqLjBYI/italian-pink-floyd-day-ii-and-launch-of-floydseum.html</link>
			<description>Last month we told you about Pink Floyd Day II (http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/latest/italian-pink-floyd-day-ii-this-saturday.html) which was being held in Brescia, Italy, on April 27th. The event proved a great success, with a resounding response from the public that spent all afternoon enjoying the exhibition of rare Pink Floyd material from private collections [see pictures, right, kindly supplied by Alberto Durgante]. 


Along with the exhibition was the official launch press conference of the new initiative known as the Floydseum (http://www.floydseum.org), a virtual, 3D museum dedicated to the world of collecting Pink Floyd, a museum that had visitors praising the  beauty and the high degree of technological innovation . In addition to this the Floydseum offered an exhibition of rare autographed prints (mostly autographed by the late Storm Thorgerson) and live photos of Pink Floyd made ??available by collectors from around the world. The stand of Floydseum was also visited by the host of the evening, live vocalist for Pink Floyd in the band's latter years, Durga McBroom, who signed many autographs, as well as a special  Wall  of signatures and dedications, before heading to the stage to perform with Italian Floyd tribute band, Wit Matrix. Durga sang several songs including a sweet  The Great Gig in the Sky  dedicated to Storm.


More information on the Floydseum comes courtesy of Rolling Stone magazine in Italy, who have just published an interview (in Italian, naturally) with Alberto Durgante (http://www.rollingstonemagazine.it/cultura/interviste-cultura/pink-floyd-arriva-il-primo-museo-virtuale/). (For an English translation, click here (http://translate.google.com/translate?sl=it tl=en js=n prev=_t hl=en ie=UTF-8 eotf=1 u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.rollingstonemagazine.it%2Fcultura%2Finterviste-cultura%2Fpink-floyd-arriva-il-primo-museo-virtuale%2F).)


RS note that 'it is the first time that Waters and his associates are seen dedicated in an entire  virtual museum , where adoring fans and curious music lovers can delight to admire very rare pieces from private collections, jealously kept secret until today. Durgante said that he, along with a handful of others, were  passionate collectors, who for many years have formed a network of friends and colleagues around the world, and wanted to build something that, albeit virtual, could remain over time. The Pink Floyd, for what they represent, deserve to be preserved and transmitted to future generations. '


Durgante was keen to point out that it wasn't an opportunity for people to boast about their collection.  For us it is the opposite. Our goal is not only to unite people with a common passion around the world but also to share, with the greatest possible number of fans, these unique items that not everyone can afford - and even those who can afford it cannot have them all - showing the beauty of those objects...  Click here to visit the Floydseum (http://www.floydseum.org) which over time will grow to what we suspect will be an essential, and fascinating, resource.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~4/3CHTuqLjBYI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2013 20:02:05 +0100</pubDate>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/latest/italian-pink-floyd-day-ii-and-launch-of-floydseum.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
			<title>Pink Floyd Live At Pompeii - remastered, Paris screenings</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~3/XAqkj92kUXE/pink-floyd-live-at-pompeii-remastered-paris-screening.html</link>
			<description>Pink Floyd Live At Pompeii (http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/live-at-pompeii/in-depth-analysis-part-one.html), the band's much-loved movie which had them performing a live set in the deserted Italian ruins. Later, footage from Abbey Road was added, giving an insight into the band during those days. For those who've yet to read it, our indepth interview with director Adrian Maben (http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/other-related-interviews/adrian-maben-live-at-pompeii-2003-with-brain-d.html) is a fascinating look at the whole Pompeii project.


Adrian has been back in touch with us this week. He told us that the Pompeii footage  has been fully restored and remastered from the original negative  and is now in a high definition, 2K format. The sound has also been improved. Full of enthusiasm for the transfer, he noted that the colour is wonderful, and the depth of the picture was remarkable - as if it was a modern day recording.


This new footage is getting its first public airing this Friday, May 3rd, at 7:30pm at La Cin&amp;eacute;math&amp;egrave;que fran&amp;ccedil;aise (http://www.cinematheque.fr/), which is on Rue de Bercy in Paris. The film will be presented by Adrian along with Belgian cinematographer Willy Kurant, who also worked on Pompeii. Tickets for this very special event are now available directly through the cinematheque.fr website (http://www.cinematheque.fr/fr/infospratiques/billetterie-cinema/achat-en-ligne.html?Session_OID=84b4f2a5-ab99-4d52-a965-000000000371).


UPDATE, May 2nd: Adrian has just informed us that there will now be a second screening at the Cin&amp;eacute;math&amp;egrave;que on May 25th at 5pm. Tickets will be available as above for the additional screening.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~4/XAqkj92kUXE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2013 22:07:11 +0100</pubDate>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/latest/pink-floyd-live-at-pompeii-remastered-paris-screening.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
			<title>Italian Floyd fanzine Heyou - new issue published</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~3/-ktaQyIRglI/italian-floyd-fanzine-heyou-new-issue-published.html</link>
			<description>Just published is the latest issue (number 22 - cover date May 2013) of the Pink Floyd fanzine  Heyou  run by our friends over at the Italian website of the same name (http://www.heyou.it/fsubscrbd.htm).


The 52-page dual language magazine (in Italian and English), which is 
published every six months or so, catches up with Floyd news from December 2012 through to the start of the current month. There's a large feature on the new Floydseum (http://www.floydseum.org) which they are saying heralds "the new era of Pink Floyd collectibles". The site aims to bring together some of the biggest collectors and enthusiasts internationally, to create a 3D virtual museum, packed with rarities from around the world for everyone to enjoy. An organic entity, the aim is for it to keep growing in size and scope. 


Elsewhere in its pages, there's an extensive look at the band's activities in 1973, a preview of the upcoming Pink Floyd Day II in Brescia, Italy, and (printed prior to his sad passing) a review of the Genesis Publications Storm Thorgerson box set, "Taken By Storm".


More details of the Heyou fanzine can be found at www.heyou.it/fsubscrbd.htm (http://www.heyou.it/fsubscrbd.htm), where you can get individual copies, and subscription enquiries (four issues costing 30 euros within Europe, and 40 euros outside Europe) should go to durgaheyou@libero.it (mailto:durgaheyou@libero.it) - make sure you mention Brain Damage when you write!&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~4/-ktaQyIRglI" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 20:57:53 +0100</pubDate>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/latest/italian-floyd-fanzine-heyou-new-issue-published.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
			<title>Italian Pink Floyd Day II this Saturday</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~3/ovCYpQlKp-E/italian-pink-floyd-day-ii-this-saturday.html</link>
			<description>Pink Floyd Day II (http://www.pinkfloydday2.it) takes place 
this Saturday, April 27th, at PalaBrescia, with Italian enthusiasts of the band holding 
their annual, national celebration of the band.


Being held to benefit the charity AIL Brescia, the day will be entirely dedicated to Pink 
Floyd, their music, their thoughts, their images, with the participation of a wide variety 
of guests, each in their own way representative of a different aspect of the band.


The event will be presented by Dario Salvatori, one of the most famous Italian music 
critics, author, and TV presenter. Amongst the guests will be Heyou fanzine; the people 
behind Floydseum, the first 3D virtual Floyd museum who will bring along some of their 
rarities for fans to enjoy; author Alexander Martorelli presenting his new book  Even Pink 
Floyd Can Go Wrong  which has already had much critic praise, alongside other guests.


Vintage guitars will be on display, alongside some incredibly rare Floyd memorabilia 
brought along by some of the most notable Italian Floyd collectors. 


The day ends with a big concert by one of the biggest Italian Floyd tribute bands, Wit 
Matrix. For the occasion, they will be joined by Durga McBroom-Hudson from Los Angeles, 
singer with Pink Floyd on the road since 1987, who will be also present in the afternoon at 
the conference and available to fans for photos and autographs.


The event starts at 4pm, and for more information visit www.pinkfloydday2.it (http://www.pinkfloydday2.it).&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~4/ovCYpQlKp-E" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 21:48:41 +0100</pubDate>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/latest/italian-pink-floyd-day-ii-this-saturday.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
			<title>Storm Thorgerson - more tributes</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~3/v6yCXFequCA/storm-thorgerson-more-tributes.html</link>
			<description>StormThorgerson.com (http://www.stormthorgerson.com) had an update from the colleagues of Storm, who very sadly passed away on Thursday.  In accordance with Storm's wishes, the studio will continue to work through this sad time and into the foreseeable future. The team remains in place, steered by Peter Curzon, Rupert Truman and Dan Abbott, and will continue the work of creating 'normal but not' images while having a cup of tea and thinking about 'it'.  Accompanying their update is the image to the right.


Elsewhere this weekend, news media across the world paid tribute to Storm Thorgerson, who very sadly passed away on Thursday. This was in the form of articles, tributes and even political/topical cartoonists using Storm's images as the basis of their regular submissions.


In amongst the obituaries, was a tribute from Aubrey 'Po' Powell, who worked with Storm for many years, that was published in the UK's The Guardian (http://www.guardian.co.uk/artanddesign/2013/apr/19/storm-thorgerson). Within his reflections, Po notes that  Storm's ideas were extraordinary, but the execution even more so. He insisted on creating real sculptures for each of his projects. Everything had to be built and photographed in situ to a size determined by the idea. No fakery, no Photoshop, or no deal.


 Things were never made easy for Storm's clients. He was a lateral and fearless thinker for whom the presentation of ideas was like a game of intellectual charades, with a few clues as to the meaning of the work thrown in every now and again. More often than not, the images he produced were unrelated to the original brief, and so it became a marathon task to interpret what came out of Storm's head.


 Always late, nearly always forgiven; full of quips, some not always appreciated; far too clever for his own good, but with a crazily gifted mind; rarely compromising, always fighting to the end, and wearing obstruction down in the belief of his own work, Storm rarely lost his way. The boy done good.  For the full article, click here (http://www.guardian.co.uk/artanddesign/2013/apr/19/storm-thorgerson).


Finally, following on from David Gilmour's comments, Nick Mason's tribute to his old friend was posted on PinkFloyd.com (http://www.pinkfloyd.com/news/index.php). Nick said:  Scourge of management, record companies and album sleeve printers; champion of bands, music, great ideas and high, sometimes infuriatingly high, standards. Defender of art over commerce at all times, and tireless worker right up to the end. Two days before he passed away, and by then completely exhausted he was still demanding approval for art work and haranguing his loyal assistants.


 Dear friend to all of us, our children, our wives (and the exes). Endlessly intellectual and questioning. Breathtakingly late for appointments and meetings, but once there invaluable for his ideas, humour, and friendship. Irreplaceable and unforgettable, but leaving a wonderful legacy of ideas, film, writings and art work, Hipgnosis and Storm have contributed to so many musicians to engineer sums immeasurably greater than their parts.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~4/v6yCXFequCA" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2013 22:33:01 +0100</pubDate>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/obituaries/storm-thorgerson-more-tributes.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
			<title>Ron Geesin live performance tomorrow evening</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~3/XL5X_06Z3-s/ron-geesin-live-performance-tomorrow-evening.html</link>
			<description>Ron Geesin, the composer and musician who worked with Roger Waters on the soundtrack to the movie, The Body (and subsequent soundtrack album), and with the Pink Floyd on their 1970 epic, Atom Heart Mother, appears at the De La Warr Pavilion, Bexhill (http://www.dlwp.com/event/dear-serge) tomorrow, Saturday April 20th, as part of a Serge Chermayeff exhibition.


 Dear Serge  is an homage to the forward-thinking mind of Serge Chermayeff - an architect, designer, thinker and prominent educator - who the Pavilion proudly has as part of its history. The event - for which tickets are free - runs from 2pm to 10pm, and Ron's performance is scheduled between 9:20pm - 10pm. Facing Ron Geesin is described as  a vibrant probing of the ether through piano, banjos, bass-xylophone, percussion and throat. Wholly consumable see the manic expressive at play.  Should be a hugely fun performance and very much worth attending.


For more information, visit the De La Warr Pavilion's website (http://www.dlwp.com/event/dear-serge).&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~4/XL5X_06Z3-s" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2013 22:48:36 +0100</pubDate>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/latest/ron-geesin-live-performance-tomorrow-evening.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
			<title>Storm Thorgerson passes away</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~3/s_D6On68478/storm-thorgerson-passes-away.html</link>
			<description>It is with a very heavy heart that we bring you the sad news that Storm Thorgerson, a key part of Pink Floyd for most of their career, passed away this afternoon (Thursday, April 18th). His family said that  his ending was peaceful and he was surrounded by family and friends. He had been ill for some time with cancer though he had made a remarkable recovery from his stroke in 2003. He was in his 70th year. 


He is survived by his mother Vanji, his son Bill, his wife Barbie Antonis and her two children Adam and Georgia. Our thoughts and condolences are with them and with his many friends across the world. From a personal perspective, in more recent years we had moved from being mere acquaintances, to friends, and I will really miss his wit, his kindness, his insight and his searching mind.


David Gilmour has made the following statement:


 We first met in our early teens. We would gather at Sheep's Green, a spot by the river in Cambridge and Storm would always be there holding forth, making the most noise, bursting with ideas and enthusiasm. Nothing has ever really changed.


 He has been a constant force in my life, both at work and in private, a shoulder to cry on and a great friend.


 The artworks that he created for Pink Floyd from 1968 to the present day have been an inseparable part of our work.


 I will miss him.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~4/s_D6On68478" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 23:46:14 +0100</pubDate>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/obituaries/storm-thorgerson-passes-away.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
			<title>Nick Mason interview - Abbey Road Studios, London, March 22nd 2013</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~3/6GOp-u2Y_XM/nick-mason-interview-abbey-road-studios-london-march-22nd.html</link>
			<description>Friday night, to kick off the weekend of celebration, marking the 40th anniversary of Pink Floyd's The Dark Side of the Moon, a handful of us escaped from the strong winds and sleet falling in the roads around St John's Wood, for the warmth and history of Abbey Road Studios. 


We convened in the Floyd's favoured recording space, Studio 3, which Nick said was different to when they used to use it, as then, the control room was on the other side of the glass (where the studio space now is). 


A full playback of the album from the SACD (played through some apparently eye-wateringly expensive surround speakers) followed an absorbing Q A with Nick Mason, hosted by Mark Jeeves (Planet Rock Radio)...


- After this period of time since its release, do you listen to it differently? 



I've never deliberately put on anything we've ever done, I think, just to take a listen to 
it, because basically I find you always listen for things that you think, 'I'd not do it 
like that now'. It's interesting because sometimes you do hear elements of it that you 
think, that DOES work. That's well done. Sadly, never the drums!


We were very proud of [The Dark Side of the Moon], and we were grateful that people were 
still interested in it [years after], but we were busy with the next thing, working on Wish 
You Were Here, or The Wall, or whatever, so it felt a bit like ancient history.


- Although it's changed a lot physically, do you think Abbey Road contributed anything to 
the album?



That's always the question I get - why do I think the record did so well? What I tend to 
firmly believe is that it's not for any one reason. It's a collection of elements that came 
together to make it work. One of those ingredients - well probably more than one - two or 
three - were Abbey Road, because the record is still seen as sonically really good and that 
was partly down to the maintenance staff here, and partly down to Alan Parsons. Without him 
I think it would have ended up not quite as good.&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~4/6GOp-u2Y_XM" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 16:32:42 +0100</pubDate>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/nick-mason-interviews/nick-mason-interview-abbey-road-studios-london-march-22nd.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
		<item>
			<title>"Pigs Might Fly: The Inside Story Of Pink Floyd" 2013 edition - Mark Blake</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~3/YVKJ2XH4TcE/pigs-might-fly-the-inside-story-of-pink-floyd-2013-edition-mark.html</link>
			<description>Pigs Might Fly: The Inside Story of Pink Floyd (http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/books/pigs-might-fly-the-inside-story-of-pink-floyd-mark-blake.html) (known as Comfortably Numb in the US) was published. Drawing on his own interviews with all of the band members, plus almost a
hundred new interviews with the group's friends, road crew, producers, 
designers, former housemates and university colleagues, the book is from
our perspective, a superb, incredibly detailed, and essential look at 
the band's history. Our review of the original edition here (http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/books/pigs-might-fly-the-inside-story-of-pink-floyd-mark-blake.html).


Yesterday - March 8th, 2013 - a new, fully updated edition of the book was published by Aurum. We've carefully gone through the new edition, comparing it with the original. As you'll see below, with an additional chapter detailing their most 
recent activities, additional interview material, and various amendments
throughout the book, the new edition should prove an indispensable 
addition to your bookshelves.


Read on to find out how the new edition differs, how to order your copy, and how to be in with a chance of winning one of FIVE copies of the book, too!&lt;img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/brain-damage-news/~4/YVKJ2XH4TcE" height="1" width="1"/&gt;</description>
			<pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2013 11:58:05 +0100</pubDate>
		<feedburner:origLink>http://www.brain-damage.co.uk/books/pigs-might-fly-the-inside-story-of-pink-floyd-2013-edition-mark.html</feedburner:origLink></item>
	</channel>
</rss>
